<data>

<item>
<hl>28 April 2009 - Al Hilal Bank launches its new retail concept Al Hilal Auto</hl>
<dn>
Abu Dhabi 28 April 2009: Aimed at providing customers a one stop finance solutions for automobiles, Al Hilal Bank will offer the convenience of shopping mall experience to its customers. Vehicle registration, takaful, choice of range of cars coupled with in-house credit analyst all under one roof, allowing customers to have their car financed in one convenient trip to the Al Hilal Auto unit within the Financial Mall located at Corniche Abu Dhabi. 

Under the patronage of Sheikh Mohammad Bin Sultan Ben Hamdan Al Nahyan, alhilal bank celebrate the launch of Al Hilal Auto, the bank is arranging a walk-in finance promotion for all automobiles. The Auto festival will feature models from all major auto dealers and customers can walk-in, chose the model and provide requisite documents like bank statements, pass port or valid ID, and drive-out their dream car 

On display at Al Hilal Auto will be a range of cars, contemporary retail ambience for the customer journey, innovative finance solutions, and a stand in credit officer and auto specialists to assist the discerning customer on choice and finance solutions. 

Speaking on the occasion Mr. Mohamed Zaqout, EVP and Head of Personal Banking said "Owning their dream car should be hassle free for our customers. With our unique customer centric model our team is assembled to ensure the formalities including a test drive, documentation, finance approval, takaful and vehicle registration can be completed within one hour. This emulates to our promise of Walk in and Drive Out" 

'The Al Hilal Auto concept is based on the fact that everything that the customer needs is all under one roof. Not only are we able to exhibit a full portfolio of our vehicle range that will suit a range of individual requirements and budgets, but we are also able to make life easier and convenient for discerning automobile buyers.' Concluded Zaqout. 

Launched in June last year, Al Hilal Bank won the best in customer service by Ethos consultancy and its flag ship Financial Mall won the best customer experience award

</dn></item>


<item><hl>26 April 2009 - Al Hilal Bank wins Gold at the Pan Arab Web Awards</hl>
<dn>
Dubai, 26 April 2009: Al Hilal Bank received two Gold awards for their web site at the Pan Arab Web Awards 

Presented to the bank last night, at a ceremony held at Burj Al Arab, Al Falak Ballroom, Dubai, the gold awards were given based on online excellence, personalization and ease of navigation. 

The Bank's web site www.alhilalbank.ae won two Golds in Finance category under Corporate and Consumer segments. The awards are judged by the industries experts on key parameters such as Concept, ease of use, structure, interactivity and design aesthetics. 

The web site is designed to cater to all age and income segments and has built-in gadgets for the user which make it convenient, personalize based on individual needs and is structured to aid in faster content updates 
Commenting on their success Mr. Mohamed Zaqout, EVP and Head of Personal Banking quoted "' we are delighted to receive Pan Arab Web Awards and will proudly add them to our collection of accolades since our launch in June 2008. During these difficult times, being customer centric and focusing on their requirements is critical and we have successfully maintained our focus and tailored customer solutions. 
Our web site revolves around the customer's requirements and is engaging, user friendly and is interactive. Web site forms a very critical touch point for our brand and we wanted our customers and our prospects to experience our personalized services. This web site will definitely be a benchmark for other financial institutions on customer centricity" concluded Zaqout. 
Launched in June last year, Al Hilal Bank won the best in customer service by Ethos consultancy and its flag ship Financial Mall AT Abu Dhabi won the best customer experience award 

About Pan Arab Web Awards 
Pan Arab Web Awards aims to serve as an inspiration, archive and at the same time reward creators for their skills so that they continue to improve it. It is also to promote the innovative spirit of web designers to meet professional and international standards, to promote intellectual and production opportunities, as well as to develop an interactive proactive and reactive community that aims at providing recognition to this e-sector in the most superlative way. Furthermore, Pan Arab Web Awards is an encouragement for all sectors to showcase their websites and be more involved in the IT
</dn></item>



<item><hl>07 April 2009 - Al Hilal Bank and SEWA sign Memorandum of Understanding to assist customer service needs</hl>
<dn>

Al-Hilal Bank in strategic tie-up with SEWA to facilitate customer bill payment processes. 

Al-Hilal Bank, the freshest face in Islamic Banking, signed a memorandum of understanding with Sharjah Electricity and Water Authority (SEWA), the Electricity and Water distribution Company, allowing customers to process their utility bills payment through the bank's channels. 

The MOU was signed on 7th April by Mr. Ibrahim Rashid, Deputy Director General from SEWA and Mohamed Zaqout Head of Personal Banking of Al-Hilal Bank. 

"We are pleased to announce our partnership with SEWA as our latest move to increase services and convenience for our customers" said Mohamed Zaqout, EVP and Head of Personal Banking, Al Hilal Bank 

"Al-Hilal Bank is setting up innovative and diverse payment systems in line with modern technology for the convenience of our mutual customers; this strategic partnership allows the bank to offer new facilities for SEWA bills payment in an online environment, and through the various channels of the bank" continued Zaqout. 

Launched in June 2008, Al-Hilal Bank prides itself in taking a progressive approach to providing its customers with accessible Shariah-compliant banking solutions. It has been a major player in a number of strategic partnerships since its launch, namely with Etihad Airways, Etisalat and the Abu Dhabi Fund for Development. 

Most recently, the bank's branch network has witnessed uninterrupted expansion, with the latest opening of Al Hilal Bank - RAK Branch that was inaugurated by H.H. Sheikh Saud Bin Saqr Al Qasimi Crown Prince of Ras Al Khaimah last month and him becoming the first customer, allowing for even easier access to its Shariah-compliant services. Additionally, Al Hilal Bank's flagship branch, The Financial Mall at Al Sahel Towers, Corniche - Abu Dhabi, received industry accolades at the Middle East Retail Banking Awards when it won the award for Best Customer Experience.


</dn></item>



<item><hl>31 March 2009 - Al Hilal Bank to establish the first Islamic bank in Kazakhstan</hl>
<dn>

Al Hilal Bank to focus on consumer and corporate banking services and cater to Kazakhstanis 

Abu Dhabi, 31 March 2009: Al Hilal Bank announced today that it will be establishing an Islamic bank in Kazakhstan making it the first for alhilal outside the UAE and the first Islamic bank in the republic of Kazakhstan. 

The agreement was signed in Abu Dhabi by a high powered delegation of Kazakhstan led by H.E. Ruslan Dalinov, Deputy Minister - Ministry of Finance from the Government of Kazakhstan and H.E. Ahmed Ateeq Al Mazrouei, Chairman of Al Hilal Bank. 

The agreement marks Al Hilal Bank's first international expansion initiative. Al Hilal bank will be responsible for setting up and managing the operations of the new bank, focusing on corporate and personal banking and offering Islamic finance solutions for small and medium enterprises. 

Commenting on the occasion, H.E. Ahmed Ateeq Al Mazrouei, Chairman of Al Hilal Bank said "We are honored to be invited by the Government of the Kazakhstan to establish the first Islamic bank in the country while building on the excellent relationship between the two governments. Our unique business model is based on customer centricity, it proved successful in the UAE, and we are aiming to leverage it in Kazak market and are confident that this move will further pave the way for the development of the country's Islamic financial sector." 

Launched in June 2008, Al-Hilal Bank prides itself in taking a progressive approach to providing its customers with accessible Shariah-compliant banking solutions. It has been a major player in a number of strategic partnerships since its launch. 

With a population of close to 16 million, Kazakhstan possesses enormous fossil fuel reserves and plentiful supplies of other minerals and metals. It also has a large agricultural sector featuring livestock and grain. Kazakhstan's industrial sector rests on the extraction and processing of these natural resources. 

The GDP of Kazakhstan is around US $ 184.3 Billion
</dn></item>



<item><hl>14 March 2009 - Al Hilal Bank opens its new branch in Ras Al Khaimah</hl>
<dn>
Ras Al Khaimah, United Arab Emirates 14 March 2009, - Al Hilal Bank, one of the leading Islamic Banks in UAE, announced that it has expanded its branch network with one new branch in Ras Al Khaimah emirate allowing the Northern Emirates customers even better access to the convenient and comprehensive Shariah compliant services it provides. 

His Highness Sheikh Saud bin Saqr Al Qasimi, Crown Prince of Ras Al Khaimah became the first customer of the Branch. Currently the bank operates seven branches; three in Abu Dhabi - one of which is the award winning Financial Mall flagship branch - two in Dubai, one each in Sharjah and Al Ain 

Within the bank's first few months of operations, the establishment of a new branch in Ras Al Khaimah marks Al Hilal's entry into the Northern Emirates banking sector, setting itself up for a significant contributing role in the UAE economy. 

Speaking on the occasion H.E. Ahmed Ateeq Al Mazrouei, Chairman of Al Hilal Bank commented "Being closer to our customers was the key motive in opening our Ras Al Khaimah branch and through this branch we will offer the kind of personalized service and products that our clients have come to expect from us," 

"Even though the world is experiencing a very difficult time economically, Al Hilal Bank has only been experiencing growth and we are looking forward to how this first stage of expansion in the Northern Emirates is going to benefit our current and future customers," Mr. Mazroui continued. 

The UAE is firmly establishing itself as a global financial hub and Al Hilal Bank, with its unique approach to banking and financial services, is positioning itself to be a driving force in that process. This is underlined by the rapid expansion of Al Hilal Bank across the UAE and by the planned opening of more branches across UAE by the end of 2009

</dn></item>



<item><hl>14 February 2009 -  Al Hilal Bank announces strategic tie up with National Bonds</hl>
<dn>
National Bonds Corporation PJSC, the innovative Sharia-compliant National saving scheme, has announced a strategic partnership with Al Hilal Bank aimed at further enhancing the distribution network of National Bonds in the UAE. 

The Memorandum of Understanding (MoU) was signed by Mr. Mohammed Qasim Al Ali, Chief Executive Officer of National Bonds Corporation, and Mr. Mohamad Jamil Berro, Chief Executive Officer of Al Hilal Bank, at a ceremony held in Abu Dhabi on 11th February 2009. 

With its progressive approach to provide customers with Sharia-compliant banking services , Al Hilal Bank with head offices based in Abu Dhabi has taken major strides in the Islamic banking sector since its inception in 2008. This partnership will provide convenient access to existing and new customers of National Bonds at all Al Hilal Bank's branches that are located in various emirates across the UAE such as in Abu Dhabi (Mall Branch, Corniche, Hamdan), Dubai (Garhoud, Bur Dubai), Al Ain (Sh. Khalifa Road) in Sharjah, Al Buharia Corniche Road, and in Ras Al Khaimah (Al Muntasir Road), including the award winning flagship 'Financial Mall' branch on Abu Dhabi Corniche. 

Mr. Mohammed Qasim Al Ali, CEO of National Bonds Corporation, said: "Our strategic partnership with Al Hilal Bank, another leading Sharia-compliant entity will not only significantly enhance our distribution network but also offer a seamless service for our bondholders in line with our vision of being everyone's favourite place to save. By establishing several customer contact points in Abu Dhabi, as part of our expansion plans this year, National Bonds will be able to offer convenient services to individual bondholders in the capital, as well as various existing and potential corporate customers".

He added: "As the only saving scheme of its kind that is committed to providing innovative and personalized services to our customers, our association with Al Hilal Bank is basically in synergy with their personalised and unique approach to Islamic banking. As part of our aim to create a strong saving culture in the UAE, we are constantly exploring new avenues through which we can reach out to customers. By joining forces with Al Hilal Bank, we aim to further increase the visibility of National Bonds as the safest, innovative and most rewarding saving scheme in the region". 

Mr. Mohamad Jamil Berro, CEO, Al Hilal Bank, said: "We are pleased to work together with a pioneering financial institution like National Bonds Corporation, whose unique saving scheme has helped boost customer confidence in the current global situation. This partnership will make Al Hilal Bank an important interface for customers keen on buying National Bonds. Our efforts will be focused on making the whole process of purchasing and utilization of services simple and hassle-free". 

This partnership with Al Hilal Bank is the fifth alliance of its kind between National Bonds and an Islamic bank. The current four are Dubai Islamic Bank, Emirates Islamic Bank, Dubai Bank and Sharjah Islamic Bank. With the addition of Al Hilal Bank branches, customers will now be able to purchase bonds from over 440 outlets throughout the UAE. 

National Bonds recently declared the annual profit rate of 7.07 % for their bondholders, it is the highest return against any comparable savings scheme offered by any financial institution in the UAE. 

Bondholders enjoyed the highest growth of 17.25% in their profit rate in 2008 as compared to 6.03% in 2007, this reflects the impressive growth achieved by National Bonds in just over a period of almost three years since its launch in 2006. In addition National Bonds Corporation gives the opportunity to win 26,318 prizes worth 5 million dirhams every month and enables one bondholder to become a millionaire every month.

</dn></item>









</data>

