<data>

<item>
<p1>Personal Banking  </p1>
<i1>Our broad range of products and services are designed to meet all your personal financial needs. We have designed them keeping your requirements in mind around Shari'a principles giving you choice, flexibility and convenience while banking with us </i1>
</item>


<item>
<p1>Deposit Accounts </p1>
<i1>Ethical values with products and services that offer clear, rewarding benefits for an altogether more modern Islamic banking experience. </i1>
</item>

<item>
<p1>Finance</p1>
<i1>We offer a range of financial products and services which are honorable, yet adaptable complying with Shari'a principles and values </i1>
</item>

<item>
<p1>Credit Cards  </p1>
<i1>Al Hilal Bank Credit Cards combine ethical values with clear benefits so you can live life to the full, safe in the knowledge that you are honoring your Islamic morals and traditions. </i1>
</item>

<item>
<p1>The Financial Mall  </p1>
<i1> For the first time in the region Al Hilal has conceptualized a shopping mall -"Mall Branch" experience into Personal Banking giving consumers a world class customer experience. 
Our Mall Branch is segmented across kids, youth, ladies, priority and mass retail along with a coffee shop, airline desk, Etisalat kiosk and a Walk in Drive out concept Auto Show room which showcases latest automobiles and the option of instant finance approvals  </i1>
</item>

<item>
<p1>About Corporate and Investment Banking  </p1>
<i1>It's All About You! 
Al Hilal Bank's Corporate and Investment Banking Group provides tailor made and cutting edge Shari'a compliant financial solutions for you! Our focus in Corporate and Investment Banking is all about understanding your business, your operations and your financial requirements and to provide you with Shari'a compliant financial solutions that is in harmony with your business needs. We believe that having the right financial solutions is critical to the success of a business entity. A business may not be able to reach its full potential if the right structure, for the right amount, at the right time is not available. Our banking solutions are designed to help you have the right products and structures whenever you need them most. 
In order to ensure that we deliver to you the level of banking expertise and commitment that you deserve, we have gathered a team of bankers with substantial experience in the local and regional market as well as Islamic Finance. Apart from having the market knowledge our team members also have experience in diverse industries and commerce. 
Our team is organized into Government Division, Corporate Banking Division and Institutional and Investment Banking Division. All these divisions are supported by our Product and Structuring Division that provides the Shari'a structuring expertise.  </i1>
</item>



<item>
<p1>Government Division  </p1>
<i1>Our Government Division manages all the banking and finance needs of the government as well as quasi government entities of the UAE.  </i1>
</item>



<item>
<p1>Corporate Banking Division </p1>
<i1>Our Corporate Banking team strives to provide our corporate customers with banking solutions that can further help them grow and expand their business and respond to the dynamic and changing business environment. Our team of Relationship Managers, with experience in different sectors and industries is ready to serve you whether you are a large corporate, a medium size establishment or small scale operator for your short term as well as your long term banking needs. </i1>
</item>

<item>
<p1>Institutional and Investment Banking  </p1>
<i1>Our Institutional and Investment Banking team focuses on syndicated as well as club deals. As your operation continue to grow bigger, your financing needs would also likely continue to grow. Our capabilities in Club and Syndication financing would ensure that you have access to a pool of funding from other financial institutions without you having to deal with them directly. 
Additionally, our Institutional and Investment banking team also establishes correspondent banking arrangement with other financial institutions across the world. By doing this, you can be assured that your cross border transactions, including trade finance and remittances will be attended to by capable and reputable banks.  </i1>
</item>

<item>
<p1>The Investment Unit  </p1>
<i1>Structured around offering clients the flexibility they need to realize the institutional and financial objectives. 
We provide a broad range of services, including Local Brokerage services, International Brokerage services, Structured Products, Mutual Funds, and Portfolio Management Solutions.  </i1>
</item>

<item><p1>Portfolio Management  </p1>
<i1>These are a collective investment schemes that contain an appropriate mix of or collection of investments held by an institution or a private individual - they could be customized to fit individual preferences, needs and profile. 
This personalized investment strategy takes into consideration base currencies, asset allocation, geographic orientation, market and industry sector biases.  </i1></item>

<item><p1>Fund Management  </p1>
<i1>These are a professionally-managed type of collective investment scheme that pools money from many investors and invests it in stocks, sukuks, and short-term money market instruments. They are either managed by Al Hilal Bank on behalf of its clients or provided by a 3rd Party from various providers from across the globe. 

Be it a Country fund (e.g. a UAE Fund), a Sector Fund (e.g. a Telecom Fund), or a regional fund (e.g. GCC/MENA Fund or an Emerging Markets Fund).  </i1></item>

<item><p1>Private Equity Funds  </p1>
<i1>This Asset class consists of equity exposure in operating companies that are not publicly traded on a stock exchange. They include equity investments, in mature companies that are looking for capital to expand or restructure operations, enter new markets or finance a major acquisition. 

They also refer to investments in less mature companies, for the launch, early development, or expansion of a business. They may also refer to investments in various public works (e.g., bridges, tunnels, toll roads, airports, public transportation and other public works) that are made typically as part of a privatization initiative on the part of a government entity.  </i1></item>

<item><p1>Structured Products  </p1>
<i1>A pre-packaged investment strategy which is based on a single security, a basket of securities, indices, commodities, and/or foreign currencies. Structured products were created to meet specific needs that cannot be met from the standardized financial instruments available in the markets. Structured products can be used as an alternative to a direct investment, as part of the asset allocation process to reduce risk exposure of a portfolio, or to utilize the current market trend. 

We are also able to provide customers with Structured Products on Commodities, Equities, Indices, Foreign Exchange... etc, and with a customizable tenor or payout structures based on the clients requirements and needs. </i1></item>

<item><p1>The Treasury Unit </p1>
<i1>We offer treasury solutions to corporate treasurers, CFO's, fund managers, Federal entities and other financial institutions enabling them to manage their Assets and Liabilities through these instruments  </i1></item>

<item><p1>Foreign Exchange  </p1>
<i1>We provide a wide range of Shari'a compliant products including Foreign exchange contracts including spot, forward, cross-currency swaps, options and other structured products, to assist our customers in their FX risk management needs.  </i1></item>

<item><p1>Money Market </p1>
<i1> We provide our clients with competitive profit rates, providing them best rates of return on their investments within the available Shari'a compliant products and services </i1></item>

<item><p1>Treasury Sales  </p1>
<i1>The Treasury Sales team helps institutional, corporate, and commercial clients in managing the risks associated with volatile Foreign exchange markets, as well as helping customers earn a higher yield on their investments through the marketing of structured investment products.  </i1>
</item>

<item>
<p1>Our products, services and their definitions:  </p1>


<item><p1>FX Spot:  </p1>
<i1>FX Spot foreign exchange is the transaction of buying and selling of currencies with two business day's delivery after the dealing date. 
Commonly used by corporate customers as well as high-net worth individuals to cover their foreign exchange exposures. 
To enter into a FX Spot deal, our customer needs to advise us of the amount, the two currencies involved, and which currency they would like to buy or sell. We deal across currencies   </i1></item>

<item><p1>FX Wa'ad (Forward) </p1>
<i1>The Islamic FX Wa'ad (Forward) allows customers to exchange one currency against another at a future date at a pre-agreed rate. 
A Wa'ad is a unilateral promise, which is only binding on the Promisor and not on the Promisee. 
This is another product which is usually used by corporate customers to cover their foreign exchange exposures. To enter into a FX Wa'ad (Forward) contract the customer needs to advise us of the amount, the two currencies involved, the settlement date, and which currency to buy or sell on the settlement date. We deal across currencies. This product is for hedging or cost-reduction purposes and cannot be traded for speculative purposes. </i1></item>

<item><p1>Profit Rate Swap  </p1>
<i1>Key instrument in managing investment and funding risk. 
A customer with an outstanding loan can eliminate the profit rate risk by entering into a Profit Rate Swap and fixing the cost over the term of loan. 
The Profit Rate Swap is based on a series of Murabahas paying a fixed profit against another series of Murabahas paying a floating profit based on a benchmark such as LIBOR or EIBOR. There is no exchange of notional amounts involved in these transactions. The only flows arising in this transaction are the net amount to be paid by one of the parties at the time of the profit payments. 
This product can be used only for hedging or cost-reduction purposes and cannot be traded for speculative purposes.  </i1></item>

<item><p1>Cross Currency Swap  </p1>
<i1>Murabaha based instrument to manage funding and investing risks when using different currencies. Cross Currency Swaps allow investors who hold Currency 1 to invest in Currency 2 for a defined period of time to mitigate currency risk. 
This product can be used only for hedging or cost-reduction purposes and cannot be traded for speculative purposes.  </i1></item>


<item><p1>Wakala Deposit  </p1>
<i1>An Islamic Money Market instrument which gives an expected profit rate over an investment period, replacing the conventional deposit. 
Wakala deposits can be placed with Al Hilal Bank in both UAE Dirhams as well as US Dollars.  </i1></item>

<item>
<p1>Murabaha Deposit </p1>
<i1>Purchase and sale of Shari'a compliant commodities, between Al Hilal Bank and our customers, which results in a Murabaha deposit. 
Murabaha deposits can be placed with Al Hilal Bank in both UAE Dirhams as well as US Dollars. </i1>
</item>
</item>
</data>

